<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Posts on Open Bytes</title><link>https://mrhedmad.github.io/blog/posts/</link><description>Recent content in Posts on Open Bytes</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>CC-BY 4.0 - Luca Visentin - 2024</copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 25 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://mrhedmad.github.io/blog/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Future Open Research</title><link>https://mrhedmad.github.io/blog/posts/future_research/</link><pubDate>Fri, 25 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mrhedmad.github.io/blog/posts/future_research/</guid><description>&lt;p>In this piece, I hope to give an overall view of how I believe the future research &amp;ldquo;flow&amp;rdquo; should look like, given the ideas in the Open Science and FAIR spaces, and how data stewards fit into the overall picture.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;d like to place a disclaimer here. I am, in no shape or form, thinking that the ideas presented here would be easy to implement. However, I believe that delineating and keeping in mind the &lt;em>golden standard&lt;/em> is essential while pursuing it.
These ideas also apply to &lt;em>publicly funded&lt;/em> research. Privately funded research might not fit this schema, although I&amp;rsquo;d argue many aspects can be transversal.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>On two-dimensional qualitative LMs for gene expression analysis</title><link>https://mrhedmad.github.io/blog/posts/on_2d_lm_deas/</link><pubDate>Thu, 16 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mrhedmad.github.io/blog/posts/on_2d_lm_deas/</guid><description>&lt;p>When dealing with differential gene expression analyses (DEAs), one can often
come across a difficulty of interpreting the linear models that are used to
detect differentially expressed genes, especially when more than one
experimental variable is considered.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Both the &lt;code>limma&lt;/code> and &lt;code>DESeq2&lt;/code> packages are very famous packages for running DEAs. They both
use linear models (LMs) - generalized linear models (GLMs) for &lt;code>DESeq2&lt;/code>- to
model the expression of every gene across all considered conditions, and use
the associated p-values and beta coefficients of the resulting models to detect
DEGs.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Arch Linux Installation</title><link>https://mrhedmad.github.io/blog/posts/archinstall/</link><pubDate>Sun, 10 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mrhedmad.github.io/blog/posts/archinstall/</guid><description>&lt;p>These are my short notes on installing Arch on my laptop (an Asus Zenbook 14).
It has UEFI Boot and a single hard disk of 500Gb. It has an Italian keyboard
(&lt;code>it&lt;/code>), a NVIDIA card and an Intel processor.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Mandatory disclaimer: Do not follow this guide. Follow the real guide over in
the &lt;a href="https://wiki.archlinux.org/title/installation_guide">Arch wiki&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;h2 id="get-an-installation-iso">Get an installation ISO&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Download from &lt;a href="https://www.archlinux.org/download/">www.archlinux.org/download/&lt;/a> the latest ISO and ask a friend with
windows to use &lt;a href="https://rufus.ie/en/">Rufus&lt;/a> to make a bootable USB stick with
it. Say thanks and buy them a snack.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>